Hi, I'm Gregg Pollack
嗨，我是格雷格·波拉克
In this video,
在这个视频中，
we'll be looking at why the composition API was created for vue3.0
我们将了解为什么要为vue3.0创建组合API
We'll start by taking a look at the limitations of vue2.0,
我们首先看一下vue2.0的局限性，
and then look at how vue3.0 solve these problems for us.
然后看看vue3.0是如何为我们解决这些问题的。
There are three limitations you may run into when using you to create components.
在您创建组件时可能会遇到三个限制。
The first is as your components grow and get bigger and uglier,
第一个是随着组件增长，它们变得越来越大、越来越丑，
they become less readable and therefore less maintainable
因此可读性、可维护性变得更差了
The second is that as you reuse pieces of code across components
第二个问题是，当您跨多个组件重用代码片段时
each of these code reuse patterns in Vue2.0 has its drawbacks
Vue2.0中的每种代码重用模式都有其缺点
The 3rd is that Vue2.0, has limited Typescript support.
第三个是Vue2.0对Typescript的支持有限。
There's ways to write it with Typescript,
有办法用TypeScript来写vue2代码
but they're not completely optimal.
但它们并不是最优的。
Let's dive into the first limitation,
让我们深入到第一个限制，
which is that large components may be hard to read and maintain.
那就是大的组件可能难以阅读和维护。
Let's imagine we're creating a simple search component,
想象一下我们正在创建一个简单的搜索组件，
you know a search bar that looks like this,
你知道一个像这样的搜索栏，
using the regular component syntax,
使用常规组件语法，
we would create a .vue file which might have a data option with reactive properties.
我们将创建一个.vue文件，它可能有一个带响应式属性的data选项。
And our methods for our search logic.
以及搜索逻辑的方法。
Once Complete,we realize we need some sorting functionality.
一旦完成，我们意识到我们需要一些排序功能。
So we write up the code,
所以我们继续堆代码，
which also has some reactive properties and some methods.
它也具有一些响应式属性和方法。
Our code for each feature, as you can see,is split up between two options.
就像你看到的，每个功能的代码都被分为两个选项。
Things aren't too messy,but they would be if we added additional functionality for say
事情还不会太混乱，但是如果我们增加额外的功能，比如说
search filters and pageination.
搜索过滤和分页。
The problem here is that logical concerns or features
这里的问题是逻辑关系或特性
are organized by component options.
按组件选项组织。
And there's a lot of component options in Vue,
Vue中有很多组件选项，
things like components, props, data computed methods,and life cycle.
比如components、props、data、计算属性和生命周期。
Our feature code might be divided up into six different places.
我们的功能代码可能会被分成六个不同的位置。
And if you think about a more complex component,
如果你考虑一个更复杂的组件，
having our code split up in multiple places
把我们的代码分散在多个地方
just isn't as nice as having it all organized together,
这肯定不如把它们都组织在一起好，
which makes our component more readable and maintainable
这使我们的组件更具可读性和可维护性
Even in our simple example,
即使在我们这个简单的例子中，
it'd be nice if our search code and our sort code was kept together and Vue3.0 makes this possible.
如果我们能把搜索代码和排序代码放在一起也会很好，Vue3.0就能让这成为可能。
Using the composition API,
使用composition API，
we can keep our components more readable.
我们可以让我们的组件更具可读性。
This all starts with the new setup method inside of our components.
这些都是从我们组件新的setup方法开始的。
Inside the new setup function is where we can start using the composition API syntax.
在新的setup函数中，我们可以开始使用Composition API语法。
And this syntax is completely optional.
这个语法是完全可选的。
We can still continue to code up components like we have before using the regular syntax.
我们仍然可以使用常规语法继续编写组件。
I knew when I first saw this, I was saying, wait,
我第一次看到这个的时候，我在说，等等，
does this mean I create a gigantic setup method with a ton of code?
这是否意味着我用大量的代码创建了一个巨大的setup方法？
And the answer here is now
答案就是现在
with Vue3.0，you end up writing composition functions.
使用Vue3.0，你最终会编写合成函数。
These are outside of your setup method.
这些是在setup方法之外的。
And they could be in the same component file.
它们可能在同一个组件文件中。
Here you can see I have a use search function and a use sorting function.
这里您可以看到我有一个搜索函数和一个排序函数。
These are called composition functions.
这些被称为复合函数。
And they're called from inside the setup method.
它们从setup方法内部调用。
As you see here,
如你所见，
Don't worry.
别担心。
We'll dive into the details of the syntax later.
稍后我们将深入讨论语法的细节。
For now,
就目前而言，
just know that our code using composition functions can now be organized by logical concerns.
只要知道我们使用复合函数的代码现在可以通过逻辑关系来组织。
I wanna point out that this doesn't mean our user interface has less components.
我想指出，这并不意味着我们的用户界面有更少的组件。
I'm not gonna be writing each piece of my page in different composition functions.
我不会用不同的排版功能来写我的每一页。
I'm still gonna have multiple components for each part of my user interface.
我还是会有多个组件为我的用户界面的每个部分。
The second limitation of Vue2.0 is that there's no perfect way to reuse code across components.
Vue2.0的第二个限制是，没有完美的方式在组件之间重用代码。
And Let me show you exactly what I mean.
接下来我来演示一下我的意思。
Back in our search component,
回到我们的搜索部分，
there are three ways we could extract this code for reuse using Vue2.0.
有三种方法可以使用Vue2.0提取此代码以供重用。
The first is Mixins.
首先是Mixins。
With mixins, first we would separate our code.
对于mixins，首先我们要分离代码。
Then we create a productSearchMixin,
然后我们创建一个productSearchMixin，
create a resultSortMixin
创建一个resultSortMixin
and then include the mixin and in our component.
然后将mixin包含在我们的组件中。
I'll shrink this down for simplicity.
为了简单起见我会缩小范围。
The good part about this is now our code is organized by feature.
好的部分是现在我们的代码是按特征组织的。
However,
然而，
with Mixins you can end up with property name conflicts.
使用mixins可能会导致属性名称冲突。
It's not clear if and how these mixins interact.
还不清楚这些mixins是否以及如何交互。
And We can't easily reuse this code to search and sort different things.
我们不能轻易地重用这些代码来搜索和排序不同的东西。
Like maybe if we had a list of reviews or sellers or shipping options.
比如，如果我们有一张书评、卖家或发货清单。
The second solution we might use with Vue2.0 is by creating a mixin and factory.
Vue2.0可能使用的第二个解决方案是创建一个mixin工厂
These are functions that return a customized version of a mixin.
这些函数返回mixin的定制版本。
Here you can see we have our searchMixinFactory.
这里您可以看到我们searchMixinFactory。
And Then We have our sortingMixinFactory.
然后我们有我们的sortingMixinFactory。
Then inside of our component, we import these two.
然后在我们的组件中，我们导入这两个。
Then we use each of these mixins specifying a name space,
然后我们使用这些mixin并指定一个命名空间，
and any configuration we need for each of the factories so that it can sort products.
以及每个工厂需要的配置，以便它可以给产品排序。
Now, the generic parts of search and sorting can be reused.
现在，搜索和排序的通用部分可以被重用了。
We also have clearer relationships with how our features interact.
我们也有这些特性如何互动的更清楚的关系。
However,namespacing requires strong conventions and discipline to do right.
然而，命名空间需要强大的约定和规则来做正确的事。
We still have to look inside each mixin and to see what properties it exposes.
我们仍然需要查看每个mixin的内部，并查看它暴露了哪些属性。
And mixin and factories can't be dynamically generated.
混合和工厂不能动态生成。
Another solution that solves some of these problems in Vue2.0 are scopes slots. What might that look like?
Vue2.0中解决这些问题的另一个解决方案是作用域插槽。 会是什么样子？
We'll start out with a generic search component.
我们将从通用搜索组件开始。
This has props and it has a slot.
这个有props，还有一个插槽。
Will also have a generic sorting component
还将有一个通用排序组件
which has crops for configuration and a slot.
其具有配置面板和一个插槽。
Then instead of our search component,
然后取代搜索组件，
we use these components sending in configuration specific product search.
我们使用这些组件发送特定产品搜索配置。
This address is just about every downside of mixins.
这个实现只是避免mixins的缺点。
However, it does increase indentation,
但是，它却增加了代码缺口，
which decreases readability.
会降低可读性。
Some of our configuration ends up in the template,
我们的配置最终出现在模板中，
which ideally should just contain what we want to render.
理想情况下应该仅包含我们想要渲染的内容。
Exposed properties like product search are only available
只暴露那些可用的产品搜索属性
in the template.
在模板中。
And having three instead of one component instance means it's less performance.
而拥有三个而不是一个组件实例意味着它的性能更差。
And those are the three ways you could reuse code with you too.
这三种方式也是你可以重用代码的方法。
However, in Vue3.0,
然而，在Vue3.0中，
we now have composition functions a 4th way to reuse code.
我们现在有了第四种重用代码的方式--组合函数。
Like before we have a file for a search functionality
就像之前我们有搜索功能的文件一样
and a file for our sorting functionality.
以及我们分类功能的文件。
These each contain composition functions which have a new syntax we'll get into in later lessons.
这些都包含组合函数，这些函数有一个新的语法，我们将在后面的课程中介绍。
Then inside of our search component,
在我们搜索组件内，
we include these composition functions and use them inside of our setup method,
我们在setup方法中包含并使用这些组合函数，
sending in any configuration they need.
发送他们需要的配置。
This solution uses less code.
此方案使用较少的代码。
It also builds on your existing JavaScript skills.
它还建立在您现有的JavaScript技能之上。
Since you're already familiar with functions,
既然你已经熟悉了函数，
it's much more flexible than mixins and scope slots,
它比混入和作用域插槽更灵活，
censor diss functions, intellisense auto Complete,
代码审查，自动完成
and typing likely already work in your code editor.
和输入已经可以在代码编辑器中使用。
The only downside here is that with Vue3.0,
现在使用vue3唯一的缺点是
now there are two different syntax is for defining components.
现在有两种不同的语法用于定义组件。
The regular syntax
常规语法
and this advanced composition API.
以及这个高级的composition API。
Yeah.
是的。
Should be chilly.
这不太友好
We're more togetherness, togetherness. Separate our
我们更团结，团结。 把我们和mixin分开
with Mixin.
Ah I'm excited. Ah Ooh Yeah.
啊我很兴奋。 啊哦是的。
Sweet.
很甜蜜。
Let's do it.
我们开始吧。